Guide to the Puebla Archives
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Criminal Cases, 1570-1904; Series II
  - Case against Joaquín Lozona and accomplices, for the murder of José Estévan, 1828 - 1830 (Box 10, Folder 219)
  - Testimony of the defendant Sebastián de la Cruz, accused of theft of money from the Association of Santa Patrona of Santa Catalina, 1828 - 1830 (Box 10, Folder 220)
  - Case against Felipe Zerezo, for injury to Francisco, his brother, 1828 - 1831 (Box 10, Folder 221)
  - Case against José Manuel Frías, for robbing José Flores, 1828 - 1832 (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - Case against Pablo Macário Ortega and accomplices, for abduction of María Isabel de los Santos, 1828 - 1834 (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - Case against Gregorio de la Cruz, for theft of wax from Bernardo García, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Decision concerning the case against Manuel Espinoza, for injury to José de la Cruz, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Case against Miguél Estevá and accomplices, deserters, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Case against José Gabriel, for injuries to José María, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Case concerning the escape of prisoners from Matamoros prison, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - Case against Manuel Muñoz, for robbery, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 229)
  - Case against Mateo Peréz, for escaping from prison, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 230)
  - Case against Antonio Sandovál, and others for fighting, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 231)
  - Case against scribes who do not wish to act upon petitions to revise laws, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 232)
  - Case concerning a minister who has had the case of Torrala presented to him monthly, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 233)
  - Case against Victoriano Bretón, for injuries causing the death of Miguél Chávez, 1829 - 1830 (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Case against Rafael Espejel, for injuries to Pedro José, 1829 - 1830 (Box 11, Folder 235)
  - Case against José Luis Ruíz de la Mota, for use of a lampoon, 1829 - 1830 (Box 11, Folder 236)
  - Case against José María Trujillo, for robbery, 1829 - 1830 (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Investigation of injuries to Pedro Cristóval, Claudio Antonio, and Santiago Crispini, 1829 - 1831 (Box 11, Folder 238)
  - Case concerning pardon granted to Pio Quinto Ramirez, reducing his prison term by two years, 1829 - 1831 (Box 11, Folder 239)
  - Case against Silvestre Neri and Agustín Reyes for the theft of a mule, 1829 - 1832 (Box 11, Folder 240)
  - Case against Cornelio Acevedo for murdering José Trinidad García, 1830 - 1831 (Box 11, Folder 241)
  - Case against insurrectionists of 3 May, 1829, Cuynaco, 1830 - 1831 (Box 11, Folder 242)
  - Case against José Ocotlán Gallegos, for injuries to Francisco Adán, 1830 - 1834 (Box 11, Folder 243)
  - Case against José Guadalupe Rojas, accused of crying centralism, 1830 - 1838 (Box 11, Folder 244)
  - Case against Andrés Palacios and José Guadalupe Moreno, for injuries, 1830 - 1831, (1904) (Box 11, Folder 245)
  - Case against Manuel de la Cruz and others, for robbery, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 246)
  - Case against Marcelino Fajardo, for robbery, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 247)
  - Case against Vicente Olivares, for injury to José Mariano Reyes, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 248)
  - Case against José Antonio Peréz, for carrying prohibited firearms, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 249)
  - Case against Joaquín Rosas, for serious injury to Pedro Martínez, 1831 (Box 12, Folder 250)
  - Case against Rafael Serón, taking into account the 26 Sep, 1830 Law, 1831 (Box 12, Folder 251)
  - Case against Manuel Tezizapa, for injuries to Domingo Cruz, 1831 (Box 12, Folder 252)
  - Case against insurrectionists of Xico, 1831 (Box 12, Folder 253)
  - Case against José Manuel Ayala, alias "El Gochi," for murdering Francisco Martínez, 1831 - 1832 (Box 12, Folder 254)
  - Case against Marcos de los Santos, for injuries to José de los Santos, 1831 - 1832 (Box 12, Folder 255)
  - Case against Manuel Gonzáles, for injuries to Leandro Guillermo, 1831 - 1834 (Box 12, Folder 256)
  - Case against María de la Luz Alegre for injuries to María Francisca Jiménez, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 257)
  - Petition by María Josépha Cabrera concerning the wait of her case vs. Secundino Mendieta, her husband, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 258)
  - Case against Antonio Calvo for stealing some bones out of a reliquary, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 259)
  - Case against Nazario García, for the theft of shoes, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 260)
  - Case against José María González, for the theft of clothes, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 261)
  - Case against José María Victor Gonzáles, for injuries to Bárbara Morales, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 262)
  - Case against María Guadalupe, for theft of clothes, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - Case against José Francisco Guerrero, for carrying a weapon, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 264)
  - Case against María Ignacia Guevara and María Ladrón de Guevara, for mutual injuries, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - Case against Bartolo Hernández and José de la Luz Romero concerning robbery, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 266)
  - Case against Carlos Hernández, for robbery of a tire, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 267)
  - Case against Ramon López, for injuries to Domingo de la Cruz, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 268)
  - Case against Felipe Morales, for injuries to Apolinario Jiménez, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 269)
  - Case against María Marcos Ortíz, for accomplice to robbery of María Murguia, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 270)
  - Case against Juan Bartolo Paredes, for injuries to José María Aguilar, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 271)
  - Case against Miguél Paredes for robbing a serape, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 272)
  - Case against José Luis Peréz, concerning fulfillment of a superior decree, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 273)
  - Case against Miguél Ramirez for theft of glass, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 274)
  - Case against José Marcelino Ramos, for robbery, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 275)
  - Case against María Joséfa Rivera, for injuries to Joséfa Toral, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 276)
  - Case against Manuel Saldaña, for possession of a knife, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 277)
  - Case against Simón Sánchez, for injury to María Mejía, his wife, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 278)
  - Case against Blasa Torres, for injuries to Brígida Gamboa, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 279)
  - Case against Mariano García, for theft of a navicular from the Convent of La Merced (see also folder 373), 1833 (Box 12, Folder 280)
  - Gregorio Lascano vs. the Mayor of Palmatlán, concerning infractions, 1833 (Box 12, Folder 281)
  - Case against Pedro Soto, for being a pickpocket, 1833 (Box 12, Folder 282)
  - Investigation of theft of clothes from the tannery of Mario Luna, 1833 - 1834 (Box 12, Folder 283)
  - Case against Antonio Rubio, for injuries to Manuel Castelar, 1833 - 1835 (Box 12, Folder 284)
  - Case against Rafael Martínez and others, for conspiracy to rob, 1833 - 1836 (Box 12, Folder 285)
  - Investigation of robbery and damage to the Convent of Nuestra Señora del Carmen, allegedly by José de la Luz Sánchez, 1833 - 1845 (Box 13, Folder 286)
  - Case against Juan Diego, for murdering José Manuel de la Cruz, 1834 (Box 13, Folder 287)
  - Case against Rafael Hernández and José Manuel Peréz, for robbery, 1834 (1899) (Box 13, Folder 288)
  - Investigation of robbery of two oxen and a cow of Manuel Peña by two unknown individuals, 1834 (1899) (Box 13, Folder 289)
  - Case against María Nicolaria Chávez, for injuries to María Joséfa del Castillo, 1834 - 1835 (Box 13, Folder 290)
  - Case against Manuel Flores, for abducting María Vicenta Amaro, 1834 - 1835 (Box 13, Folder 291)
  - Case against José Ignacio Gonzáles and accomplice José Antonio Cruz, for murdering Ignacio Vásquez, 1834 - 1835 (Box 13, Folder 292)
  - Case against José Justo, for murdering José Teodoro Martín, 1834 - 1835 (Box 13, Folder 293)
  - Case against Pantaleon Nazario and accomplices, for robbery, 1834 - 1835 (Box 13, Folder 294)
  - Investigation of robbery and injury to Diego Jiménez, 1834 - 1836 (Box 13, Folder 295)
  - Case against José Antonio for injuries to María Ilaria, his wife, 1835 (Box 13, Folder 296)
  - Investigation of injuries to José Manuel García, 1835 (Box 13, Folder 297)
  - Case against Manuel Gargallo, found in possession of articles belonging to José Antonio Reyes, 1835 (Box 13, Folder 298)
  - Investigation of the theft of a pig from Cirilo Méndez, 1835 (Box 13, Folder 299)
  - Case against Felipe Solis, for injuries to Anastasia Cao Romero, 1835 (Box 13, Folder 300)
  - Case against José Tomás, for injury to María Cesarea, 1835 (1899) (Box 13, Folder 301)
  - Case against Joséfa Castillo, for biting Nicolása Chávez, 1835 - 1837 (Box 13, Folder 302)
  - Case against Mariano Alsivar, for theft of a blue silk spread, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 303)
  - Case against Luciana Castilla, for injury to José Flores, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 304)
  - Investigation of injuries to José María Crispín and Matías Arje, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 305)
  - Case against Carmen Flores, for injuries to Jerónima Guzmán, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 306)
  - Petition by Margarita Flores that José Antonio Flores, her brother, be released from prison, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 307)
  - Case against José de Jesús Gutiérrez, pickpocket, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 308)
  - Investigation of mutual injuries of Antonio Hoyos and José María Vidál, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 309)
  - Case against Inés Martínez, for injuries to Francisca and Petra Suárez, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Investigation of mutual injuries of Antonio Inchanrrigue and Nicolás Ruíz, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Investigation of the death of Maríano Mendiola, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Case against Antonio Ramirez, for theft of a candelabra from the sacristy of the Convent of Carmen, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 313)
  - Investigation of injury of José Augustín Robles, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 314)
  - Case against Manuel Rodríguez, for injury to Andrés González, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - Investigation of injuries to Maríana Guadalupe Sánchez, by an unidentified man who escaped, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 316)
  - Investigation of injuries to Vicente Sánchez, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 317)
  - Investigation of the theft of a messenger, walking towards Veracruz, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 318)
  - Case against Felipe Suárez, for attempting to murder Maríana Peréz, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 319)
  - Investigation of the theft of a horse from José Florentino Telles, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 320)
  - Case against Antonio Trasloseros for injury to María Francisca Ventita, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 321)
  - Investigation of injuries to Cristóbal Varranco and Juan de Diós Rodríguez, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 322)
  - Case against Mariano García for robbing a navicular from the Convent of La Merced (see folder 330), 1836 - 1837 (Box 14, Folder 323)
  - Case against José María Castillo, for injury to Joséfa Feliciana López, 1836 - 1837 (Box 14, Folder 324)
  - Manuel Medrano vs. Mauricio Gutiérrez Fernández, for theft, 1836 - 1839 (Box 14, Folder 325)
  - Mariano Cesario vs. the Mayor, José María Monje, 1836 - 1842 (Box 14, Folder 326)
  - Investigation of the tumult in San Augustín Atzompán and of resulting injuries to the mayor and 3 citizens, 1836 - 1842 (Box 14, Folder 327)
  - Case against José María Bonilla and accomplices, for various assaults, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 328)
  - Case against José de la Luz Cabrera, for theft of a serape from José María Avila, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 329)
  - Case against María Rita Flores, for robbery of clothes from María Joséfa Martínez, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 330)
  - Case against Rafael Flórez, for robbery, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 331)
  - Investigation of the murder of José Julián Macías and of the injury of Dolores López, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 332)
  - Case against María Juliána Romero, for injury to María Ignacia Fernández, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 333)
  - Investigation of Antonio Martínez, accused of deserting the Batallion of Puebla, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 334)
  - Investigation of injury to María Guadalupe Nunez, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 335)
  - Case against Francisco Olivares, alias "Cabezón", for injury to Mariano Robles, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 336)
  - Case against Joséfa Salazar, for injury to Maríana Carrillo, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 337)
  - Investigation of the theft of two bulls belonging to Juan Teodoro, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 338)
  - Investigation of injury to member of the Regiment of Palmar Valenzuela, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 339)
  - Case against Mariano Zabedra, for injury to José María de la Soledad Hernández, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 340)
  - Case against Margarita López, for pickpocketing, 1837 - 1838 (Box 15, Folder 341)
  - Case against Francisco Peréz, for injuries to Fabian Rodríguez, 1837 - 1838 (Box 15, Folder 342)
  - Case against Silverio Peréz, for injuries to María Margarita Sotomayor, 1837 - 1838 (Box 15, Folder 343)
  - Investigation of injuries to Hignio and Pablo Telles, Fernando Bravo, and Manuel Zaragoza, 1837 - 1838 (Box 15, Folder 344)
  - Case against Miguél Varela, for robbery, 1837 - 1838 (Box 15, Folder 345)
  - Case against José Dolores, for theft of beasts, 1837 - 1839 (Box 15, Folder 346)
  - Case against Juan Augustín Soriano, for serious injury to Nicolás Francisco, 1837 - 1845 (Box 15, Folder 347)
  - Case against José Luis Gonzáles, for injuries causing death of Tiburcio Luna and Francisco Gutiérrez, 1837 - 1846 (1902) (Box 15, Folder 348)
  - Investigation of the death of Lucas Antonio, whose body was found on the Royal Road, 1838 (1899) (Box 15, Folder 349)
  - Investigation of the escape from prison of Aparicio Gonzáles, 1838 (Box 15, Folder 350)
  - Case against José María Peréz, for injury to José Cristóbal Arrieta, 1838 (Box 15, Folder 351)
  - María Andrea Roldán vs. José Antonio Yriarte, her husband, for adultery, 1838 (Box 15, Folder 352)
  - Investigation of the injuries to Pedro Sánchez, 1838 (1899) (Box 15, Folder 353)
  - Case against José Anastasio Cuaxinca, for injury to Manuel Rodríguez, 1838 - 1839 (Box 15, Folder 354)
  - Investigation of the escape of 12 prisoners, 1838 - 1839 (Box 15, Folder 355)
  - Case against María Joséfa Victoriana, for infanticide, 1838 - 1839 (Box 15, Folder 356)
  - Case against Nicolás Diego, for murdering José Mariano, his brother, 1838 - 1840 (Box 15, Folder 357)
  - Case against María de la Luz Hernández, for injuries to María Juliána Peregrina, 1838 - 1840 (Box 15, Folder 358)
  - Case against Joaquín Patricio Nopalteco for theft of burros and escape from prison, 1838 - 1841 (1902) (Box 15, Folder 359)
  - Case against José María Juárez and accomplices for robbery and murder, 1838 - 1843 (Box 15, Folder 360)
  - Investigation of the death of Pedro Santiago, 1838 - 1843 (Box 16, Folder 361)
  - Case against José Antonio Cielo, for injury to Maríana Gertrúdis, 1838 - 1846 (Box 16, Folder 362)
  - Case against Juan Torres and accomplices for assaulting the weavers of Tecamachala, 1838 - 1846 (Box 16, Folder 363)
  - Case against Pedro José Enríquez, for robbery, 1838 - 1850 (Box 16, Folder 364)
  - Case against Rafael Cardona and Francisco Macareno, for injuries to José Miguél Enríquez and for carrying a weapon, 1839 (Box 16, Folder 365)
  - Testimony of Camilo Díaz, for his part in the escape of prisoners, 1839 (Box 16, Folder 366)
  - Case against Manuel Fragoso, for assault and murder and for escaping from prison, 1839 (Box 16, Folder 367)
  - Case against Juan García, animal thief, 1839 (Box 16, Folder 368)
  - Case against Manuel Antonio Méndez, for murder of Miguél Pascual and injury to José Gerónimo, 1839 (1900, 1902) (Box 16, Folder 369)
  - Case against José Rudeano Parada, animal thief, 1839 (Box 16, Folder 370)
  - Case against José Domingo and José Nicolás, for theft, assault, and injury to José Gregorio and his wife, 1839 - 1840 (Box 16, Folder 371)
  - Case against José Nicolás, horse thief, 1839 - 1840 (Box 16, Folder 372)
  - Investigation of theft of an incense burner and navicula from San Jerónimo Achitlán, 1839 - 1841 (1902) (Box 16, Folder 373)
  - Case against Manuel Pardo and José Mariano Alarcon, for mutual injuries, 1839 - 1841 (Box 16, Folder 374)
  - Case against José Toribo Hernández and others for incest, 1839 - 1841 (Box 16, Folder 375)
  - Case against José Ventura Martínez, for the murder of Manuel de Jesús Cordero, 1839 -1842 (Box 16, Folder 376)
  - Case against José Manuel Muñoz, for robbery, 1839 - 1842 (Box 16, Folder 377)
  - Victoriano Giles vs. José Hernández, for theft, 1839 - 1847 (Box 17, Folder 378)
  - Case against Juan Martínez, animal thief, 1840 (Box 17, Folder 379)
  - Investigation of the death of Petrona María from a blow, 1840 - 1841 (1902) (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Case against José de la Luz and José Justo Benítez, for assault and robbery, 1840 - 1842 (Box 17, Folder 381)
  - Case against José Martínez, for robbery, 1840 - 1843 (Box 17, Folder 382)
  - Case against Vicente Tapia and others, for robbery, 1841 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Case against Guadalupe Santillán, for robbery, 1841 - 1842 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Case against Francisco Flórez for injury to José Peralta, 1842 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Petition by Manuel Fragoso that he be released from prison, 1842 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Case against Trinidad Rosas, for injury to José Palacios, 1842 (Box 17, Folder 387)
  - Case against Dámaso Torres, for raping Soledad Díaz, 1842 - 1843 (Box 17, Folder 388)
  - Case against José María Villalba for murdering Manuel Ramirez, 1842 - 1844 (Box 17, Folder 389)
  - Case against Francisco Tello, for beating several neighbors, 1842 - 1846 (Box 17, Folder 390)
  - Case against Cleto Pineda, for injuries to Priciliano Corona, 1843 (Box 17, Folder 391)
  - Petition by María Pantaleona Tamarillo, concerning the case against Cristóbal Tamarillo, her father, and Alejo Rojas, her husband, 1843 (Box 17, Folder 392)
  - Case against Francisco Justo and accomplices for murder, 1843 - 1846 (Box 17, Folder 393)
  - Case against Margarita Acosta, for injuries to José Sebastián López, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 394)
  - Case against María de la Luz Carillo, for pickpocketing, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 395)
  - Petition by Manuel Cartillo to Gregorio Sandovál asking to be released from prison, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 396)
  - NO FOLDER # 397
  - Case against Paulino Jimenéz, for pickpocketing, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 398)
  - Case against José de Jesús Larios, for injury to José María Pérez, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 399)
  - Investigation of injury to Francisco Nava, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 400)
  - Case against Benito Pérez, for carrying a knife, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 401)
  - Case against José María Rodríguez, for injury to María Antonia Pérez, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 402)
  - Investigation of injury to José Fermín Angel by Carlos Rojas, in prison, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - Case against Antonio Salazar, for pickpocketing, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 404)
  - Case against María Rosario Sánchez, for injury to María Ignacia Silba, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Investigation of injury to María Guadalupe Yta, 1844 (Box 18, Folder 406)
  - Case against Estéban and Andrés Cocolotl and others for inciting the population and for misdemeanors towards the Justice of the Peace and the Priest, San Andrés Cholula, 1844 - 1845 (Box 18, Folder 407)
  - The Mayor of Puebla vs. Antonio Herédia, for fraud to his creditors, 1844 - 1846 (Box 18, Folder 408)
  - Case against Antonio Maldonado, for the murder of Luis Osorio, 1844 - 1846 (Box 18, Folder 409)
  - Case against Gregoria Guerra, for injury to Antonio Vásquez, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 410)
  - Investigation of the death of José Justo, run over by a cart, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 411)
  - Investigation of the serious injury to Remigio Sid, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 412)
  - Investigation of the injuries by José Tlatelpan to Eulogio Antonio and José María Cacelín, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 413)
  - Investigation of theft of a mare by Luis Torres, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 414)
  - Case against Miguél Varela, for injuries to José María Cortéz, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 415)
  - Case against Francisco Huerta, for injury to José María Zabaleta, 1845 (Box 18, Folder 416)
  - Case against Pablo Alvino and María Dolores, for incest, 1845 - 1846 (Box 18, Folder 417)
  - Case against José de la Rosa and accomplices, for robbery and injuries, 1845 - 1846 (Box 18, Folder 418)
  - Case against Diego Casimiro and María Juliana, for incest, 1845 - 1847 (Box 18, Folder 419)
  - Investigation of the theft of a house by Eligio Zárate, 1845 - 1847 (Box 18, Folder 420)
  - Case against José Angelino and accomplices, for theft, 1845 - 1850 (Box 19, Folder 421)
  - Case against Benito Aniseto, for injuries to Pedro Pascual, 1846 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Case against Francisco Antonio, for injuries to Angelina María de Zoyoatla, his wife, 1846 (1899) (Box 19, Folder 423)
  - Case against Clemente Dominguez and Victor Barrera, for their escape from prison, 1846 (Box 19, Folder 424)
  - Investigation of assault and robbery of Antonio Jiménez, 1846 (1899) (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - Case concerning injury to Pablo Miguél Martín, 1846 (1899) (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Case against Ignacio Tufino, for robbery and excesses, 1846 (1899) (Box 19, Folder 427)
  - Case against Margarito de Jesús, for injuries to Eustaquio Mateo Mejía, 1846 - 1847 (1899) (Box 19, Folder 428)
  - Investigation of the theft of cattle by Nabor Jiménez, 1846 - 1847 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Investigation of the injury to Aniceto Trinidad, 1846 - 1847 (Box 19, Folder 430)
  - Case against Felix Antonio Venegas and Juan Agustín for theft of corn from Simón Flórez, 1846 - 1849 (Box 19, Folder 431)
  - Case against Juan de la Cruz, for theft of a shirt, 1847 (1899) (Box 19, Folder 432)
  - Case against Ciriano Torres, for theft of a horse, 1847 - 1848 (Box 19, Folder 433)
  - Case against José Ignacio Parrales, for theft of donkeys, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 434)
  - Case against Joaquín Rivadeneira, for theft of barley, 1838 (Box 19, Folder 435)
  - Case against Encarnación Rodríguez, for injury to Joséfa Salazar, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 436)
  - Case against Porfirio Sora and Leonardo Romero, for pickpocketing, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 437)
  - Case against Ciriaco Torres, for theft and resisting arrest, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 438)
  - Case against José de la Luz Torres, for fighting with José Pascual, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 439)
  - Case against Domingo Jiménez, counterrevolutionary, 1848 - 1849 (Box 19, Folder 440)
  - Case against José María Guerrero, for attempted murder, 1848 - 1851 (Box 19, Folder 441)
  - Case against Joaquín Parada, for murdering Juan López, 1848 - 1851 (Box 19, Folder 442)
  - Case against Francisco de Vivanco, for abducting María Felipa Cortés, 1848 - 1861 (Box 19, Folder 443)
  - Case against José de Jesús Baiz, for theft of jewels from Andrés Antonio Salazar, 1849 (Box 19, Folder 444)
  - Investigation of the theft of sifting cloth from José María Ceballos, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 445)
  - Investigation of injuries to Anastasia Corona, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 446)
  - Investigation of the death of Francisco Diego, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 447)
  - Investigation of injury to María Merced Galindo, 1849 (1900) (Box 20, Folder 448)
  - Case against Anastasio Luna for theft of a mule, Estévan Valerio for abduction of Maura Hernández, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Investigation of injury to Federico Maillarte, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 450)
  - Case against Marcos Paulino, for robbery, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 451)
  - Case against José Aniceto Rodríguez, for attempting the murder of Cirilo Flores, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 452)
  - Case against Vicente Romero and accomplices for robbery of the courts of Huanchinanco and Tulanzinga, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 453)
  - Investigation of the theft of a donkey, 1849 (1900) (Box 20, Folder 454)
  - Investigation of several robberies, allegedly by Laureano Enmana, 1849 - 1850 (Box 20, Folder 455)
  - Case against Miguél Pedro, Manuel Coyote and Pedro Diego, for robbery and rape, 1849 - 1850 (Box 20, Folder 456)
  - Investigation of injuries to José María Pastrana, murder of J.M. Pastrana, 1849, 1851 (1900) (Box 20, Folder 457)